嘿
Hey.
给你
Here you go.
吃吧
Here ya go.
有时候感觉事情永远不会改变
Sometimes it feels like things never change.
但我向你保证
But I promise you.
他们确实如此 他们得这样做
They do. They have to.
我并不是说这很容易
And I'm not saying it's easy.
改变伴随着失落感
Change comes with feelings of loss.
还有...
And...
我们可能会感受到阻力
We might feel resistance.
就像这世界上有许多东西需要改变
Like there's so much in the world that needs changing.
我该从哪里起步
Where am I supposed to start?
对吧
Right?
当你有这种感觉时
When you feel that way,
那是开始工作的时机
that is the moment to begin work.
无论是什么事情让你兴奋 最后都会变成是在消磨时间
On whatever fires you up, you just start chipping away.
如果你环顾这个房间四周
And if you look around this room,
你会发现你并不孤单
you'll see that you're not alone.
永远不要觉得你无能为力
Don't ever feel like there's nothing you can do.
拜托
Please.
这就是我对你们的期待
That's my wish for you.
现在你们上了这门课
And now you've taken this class
我知道你们不会羞于使用你们的语言
I know you won't be afraid to use your words.
是的
All right.
我就只能给你们讲这些 你们有90分钟的时间
That's all I've got. You have 90 minutes.
要让我骄傲
Make me proud.
做得好
Well done.
呃 吉德里教授
Uh, Professor Guidry,
我只是想说谢谢你帮我处理了
I just wanted to say thank you for dealing
我疯狂的日程安排
with my crazy schedule.
格雷琴 你真是太好了
Gretchen, that is so sweet of you,
但你才是成功人士
but you're the one who made it work.
真希望你能再给我上一门课
I wish you had another class I could take.
我喜欢教基础知识
I like teaching the basics.
正如那句流行的格言所说
As the popular aphorism goes,
“那些不会教书的人”
"Those who can't do teach,"
然而那些不会教书的人却都成为了院长
and those-- those who can't teach become deans,
“不同的谈话
'nother conversation.
乔治发挥了关键作用
George has played a critical role
多年来 在建立这个部门的文化教育中
in building the culture of this department
我们都受益于他的智慧
over the years and we have all benefited from his wisdom
我们也因他的幽默而感到振奋
and we have had our spirits lifted by his good humor.
还有 从更私人的角度上来说
And man, on a-- on a more personal note,
我只是谦卑和感激地
I am just humbled and grateful
称你为同事 导师和钓鱼伙伴
to call you a colleague, a mentor and a fishing buddy.
说真的 伙计们 这家伙会飞
Seriously, folks, this guy can cast a fly.
我见过他在一英尺深的死水里从一条棕色的鳟鱼身上爬起来
I have seen him get a rise out of a brown trout in one
我可不是在开玩笑
foot of stillwater, I am not kidding you.
不管怎么说 我已经让这个男人够难堪了
Anyway, I've embarrassed the man enough.
敬乔治
To George.
谢谢你 小伙子
Thanks, man.
要取代你的位置可不容易 乔治
It's gonna be hard to fill your shoes, George.
我就跟你说这么多
Tell ya that much.
嘿 亚瑟
Hey, Arthur.
桑德拉 你是怎么坚持下来的
Sandra, how ya holdin' up?
你还好吗
You doin' okay?
-我很好 我很好 -好的
- I'm good, I'm good. - Yeah.
我不想在会议上为难你
I didn't want to put you on the spot in the meeting,
但请接受我最诚挚的慰问
but my sincere condolences.
我很高兴她不再受苦了
I'm just glad that she's not suffering anymore.
是的 是的 她现在的处境要更好了
Yeah. Yeah. She's in a better place now.
我... 我... 我确实有个小问题
I-- I-- I did have a quick question.
好的 好吧 跟我走
Yeah. Okay, well, walk with me,
因为我得回家了
'cause I got to get home.
格雷琴 你能为这些东西
Hey, Gretchen, can you find a tote bag
找个手提包吗
for some of this stuff?
你今天早上看到一辆红色卡车了吗
Did you see a red truck this morning?
我每次睁开眼睛都能看到一辆红色卡车
I see a red truck every time I open my eyes,
实际上是一辆国产车
it's practically the state car.
-嘿 托德 -假期愉快
- Hey, Todd. - Nice holiday.
回见 圣诞快乐
See ya, merry Christmas.
我是说 在峡谷里
I mean, in the canyon.
它停在我的车道上
It was parked in my driveway.
可能是猎人吧
Probably hunters, right?
我不知道
I don't know.
呃...
Um...
你知道 苏珊几年前失去了母亲
You know, Susan lost her mom a few years back.
它... 它带来了所有悬而未决的问题
It-- it brings up all of the unresolved shit.
需要时间去消化 不要对自己太苛刻 好吗
Takes time. Just go easy on yourself. Okay?
是的 也许你是对的
Yeah, you're probably right.
我期待在圣诞晚会上见到你
And I expect to see you at the Christmas party!
会有蛋奶酒等着你的
There's gonna be eggnog!
过来
Come on!
过来 宝贝
C'mon, baby.
-早上好 女士 -早上好
- Morning, ma'am. - Good morning to you.
这里是你的黄金地段
It's a prime spot you got here.
我们只是想去树林里走走
Hey, we just figured we'd walk up into the woods.
我们不会给你添麻烦的 我们会离你远远的
We won't be any trouble for ya. We'll stay out of your hair.
你肯定收到我的便条了
You must have got my note, though.
我昨天把它放在你的卡车上了
I put it on your truck yesterday.
这是我头一回听到说有便条在我车上
That's the first I heard of any note.
上面都写了啥
What-- What did it say?
它说我不希望你把车停在这里
It said I'd prefer you not park here.
啊哈
Uh-huh.
只是这个地方没有太多
It's just there's not a lot of good jumping
好的移动点
off points around here.
你可以从另一边儿进来
You could always come in from the other side.
另一边儿
The other side?
那得有多远
How far is that?
大约15英里
About 15 miles.
15英里
Fifteen miles.
女士 我们不会在谁的住所开枪
Ma'am, we're not gonna put a bullet
或射杀谁的牛
in anyone's house or shoot anybody's cow.
我也不认为你会这样
I didn't think you were.
是的 但你明确告诉我你想让我们
Yeah, but you're telling me you want us to walk
在雪地里走15英里
15 miles in the snow.
我可不是这么说的
That's not what I said
我也没有告诉你该做什么
and I'm not telling you to do anything.
我想说的是在你把车停在别人的地盘上之前
All I'm saying is before you park
你必须得先问问人家是否同意
on someone's property, you have to ask.
我对你有所耳闻
I heard about you.
只是不知道是这个峡谷
Just didn't know it was this canyon.
好了 忘了这一茬吧
All right. Forget about her.
上车吧
Get in the truck.
太过分了
Too much.
显然 没有人反对
Look, obviously, nobody objects
这个基本概念
to the basic concept.
我只是认为 首先 我们需要
I just think, first and foremost,
审视冷酷 苛刻的限定条件
we need to look at cold, hard qualifications.
所以 正如我们一开始所说的
So, like we said, in the beginning,
我们的工作是向院长推荐三位最佳候选人
our job is to present the three best candidates to the dean.
任期
Period.
好吧 我想我只是对我们所说的
Well, I guess I'm just confused
最好的意思感到困惑
about what we mean by best.
我认为我们不应该试图填补
I don't think we should be trying to fill
某种指标
some kind of quota.
噢 当然不是 没有人强迫我们
Oh, course not. No one is forcing our hand.
这些都是我们应该
These are just factors we should consider
考虑在内的因素
among many others.
还有人想要补充吗
Um, did anyone else want to chime in?
是的 费思 你有什么要说的吗
Yes. Faith, you have a comment?
对我来说 学习就是
To me, learning is about
提问和挑战自己
asking questions and challenging yourself.
这些年来 我的一些最优秀的学生
Over the years, some of my very best students
都是来自印第安人
have been Indians from the reservation
因为他们把这种全新的体验带入了课堂
because they bring this whole other experience into class.
我认为我们可以多倾听
I think we could all stand to listen more and learn
从与我们观点不同的人的身上学到更多
more from people who don't have the same perspective as us.
你可以称之为多样性 我也不太清楚
You can call it diversity. I don't know.
在可能的情况下 吸引不同类型的人
It just seems like the right thing to do
似乎是正确的做法
to bring in different sorts of people when we can,
而不是像以前那样做
rather than doing the same old thing we've been doing.
我觉得你的观点很好 费思
I think your point's very well taken, Faith.
让我们把它列为优先事项
Let's make it a priority.
呃... 就这样吧
Um... all right.
女士 你介意为我拼一下你的姓氏吗
Ma'am, would you mind spelling your last name for me?
G-U-I-D-R-Y
G-U-I-D-R-Y.
卡桑德拉·吉德里 这是一个名字
Cassandra Guidry. That's a name.
你从哪里来
Where you from originally?
新奥尔良
New Orleans.
人们把那地方称之为 呃...
What do they call that, uh...
-啊... -好轻松
- Uh-- - The Big Easy.
好轻松 没错 我正要去那里
The Big Easy. That's right. I was getting there.
那里有很多历史 对吧
There's a lot of history down there, you know?
你在城里工作
You work in town?
我在大学里教书
I teach at the university.
是这样吗
Is that right?
你教什么科目
What subject you teach?
不好意思 这跟我们讨论的话题有关吗
I'm sorry. Is this relevant?
好吧 抱歉
Yeah. Sorry.
你说你第一次直接接触 你唯一直接接触的是
Um, you said your first direct contact-- your only direct
他们停车时的车道上
contact with them was in the driveway
当他们想要停车的时候
when they're trying to park?
两天前 没错
Two days ago. That's correct.
好的 他们当时有没有威胁过你
Okay. And, uh, did they threaten you at all that time?
不是很明显 但我肯定是
Not overtly, but I have definitely
被威胁到了
been made to feel threatened.
好的 呃...
Okay. Um...
吉德里女士
Ms. Guidry.
在自然环境中 如果你在你的地盘上截住了人
City environment, you catch somebody on your property,
这是件坏事儿 所以你应该要联系执法部门 明白吗
that's a bad thing, so you contact law enforcement, right?
在这里 情况有点不同
Out here, things are a little different.
一般来说 人们倾向于
And people, generally, they tend to handle
自己处理这类事情
this sort of thing amongst themselves.
你心里清楚 你放手不管小事儿
You know, you let the small things
是为了避免将来出现更大的问题...
go to avoid a bigger problem down the road--
警官 他们朝我的门射了一箭
Officer, they shot an arrow into my door.
我明白 但你确实拖了他们的卡车
I understand that, but you did tow their truck.
也许我不该那样做
Perhaps I should not have done that,
但我完全有权利这么做
but I was well within my rights.
噢 你当然可以
Oh, of course you were. Of course.
但你可以看到 你知道的 这种事情可能会
But you can see how that sort of thing, you know,
让一个人心烦意乱
might upset a person.
我得警告你 这两位先生
And I've got to warn you, that these two gentlemen,
他们很可能会看到你又一次把事态升级
they are likely to see you're involving the local
从而涉及到当地的治安部门
sheriff's department as yet another escalation.
你为何一直称他们为绅士
Why do you keep calling them gentlemen?
你看到他们的车牌号了吗
Did you happen to catch their license plate?
2-3-8-3-9-5
2-3-8-3-9-5.
你为什么要收集这些东西
And why did you collect all of this, exactly?
我的意思是 大多数人 他们不会想保留
I mean, most folks, they wouldn't think to keep
所有这些东西
all of this stuff.
我想我不是什么大多数人
I guess I'm not most folks.
是的 所以...
Yeah. So...
好的 感谢你抽出时间
Well, thank you for your time.
所以 接下来要怎么做
So, what happens now?
我很清楚这些人是谁
Well, I've got a pretty good idea who these boys are,
所以让我来做他们的思想工作
so I work with them,
看看我是否可以解决这个问题
see if I can't straighten this out.
好极了 我去拿外套
Great. I'll get my coat.
女士 你真的没必要和我一同前往
Ma'am, there's really no need for you to come along.
你好
Hello.
今天这里怎么样了
How's it going in here, today?
她跑来这里干什么 格斯
What is she doing here, Gus?
-女士 你有什么问题... -嘿 嘿 嘿
- Lady, what is your problem-- - Hey, hey, hey
我们放松点 好吗
Let's just relax here, okay?
你没必要和她说话
There's no need for you to talk to her.
你只管跟我说话 保持礼貌
You just talk to me. Keep it civil.
我们现在就开始吗 格斯
We're gonna do this right now, Gus?
在这里我做的是正当的工作
This is honest work I'm doing here.
你会害我被解雇的
You're gonna get me fired.
我不会害你被解雇的 我保证 好吗
I'm not gonna get you fired. I promise. Okay?
看来你们昨晚在她门上射了一箭
It seems you boys put an arrow in her door last night.
是这样吗
Is that right?
不 我什么都不知道
No, I don't know anything about that.
她有没有告诉你她差点弄坏我的车轴
Did she tell you that she damn near broke my fucking axle?
嘿 放松点 好吗
Hey, let's just relax. Okay?
她对你很坦诚
She's pretty up front with you.
她只是不希望你出现在她的地盘上
She doesn't want you on her property.
你得尊重这一点儿 好吗
You got to respect that, all right?
这很有趣
That's pretty funny.
你说的是尊重 警长
You talking about respect, Sheriff.
我不是警长 你知道的
I'm not the sheriff and you know that.
我是代理警长
I'm the acting sheriff.
好吧 该死 伙计
All right, shit, man.
-我们能结束这一切吗 -是啊 我们可以结束了
- Can we wrap this up? - Yeah, we can wrap it up.
离她那该死的房子远点儿
You stay off her goddamn property.
去找别的地方打猎吧
You find someplace else to hunt.
清楚了吗
Is that clear?
不 你得说出来
No, you gotta say it.
-是的 -是的 什么
- Yep. - Yeah, what?
-是的 我们清楚了 -好极了
- Yeah, we're clear. - Great.
酷
Cool.
在哪儿能找到你弟弟
Now, where can I find your brother?
和我预想中的不一样
Not what I was expecting.
听着 我不能阻止你跟着我
Look, I can't stop you from tagging along,
但我不是来聊天的 好吗
but I'm not here to chit chat, okay?
我们要呼叫支援吗
Should we call for backup?
什么支援 我们有两名警官在300平方英里范围内巡逻
What backup? We've got two officers to cover 300 square
其中一人目前正在行政休假
miles and one of them's currently
所以只剩下我了
on administrative leave. So that leaves me.
另一个怎么了
What happened to the other one?
关于闲聊我是怎么说的
What'd I say about chit chat?
怎么了
What?
我们要怎么做
How we doin'?
帮我个忙
Do me a favor.
把你的面具取下来 我想看看我在跟谁说话
Take your mask down, I like to see who I'm talking to.
你听到了吗 孩子
Do you hear me, son?
支持你这么做
Behind you.
下午好 先生们
Afternoon, gentlemen.
我不是要来逮捕谁的
Now, I'm not here to arrest anybody.
只是想跟你们其中一个说句话
Just need to have a word with one of you boys.
怎么回事儿 伙计们 我知道你们都能听到我在说什么
What's the deal, guys? I know you can hear me.
好了 大家往前一步
Okay. Everybody step forward!
把锯子放下 把面具摘下来
You put your saws down, you take your masks off!
还有什么 你要开枪打我们吗 沃尔夫
Or what? You're gonna shoot us, Wolf?
没有人要开枪
Nobody's shooting anybody.
是啊 你怎么不去跟我表弟说
Yeah. Why don't you tell that to my cousin.
我没开枪打你表弟...
I didn't shoot your cousin--
是你那该死的老板干的
Your piece of shit boss did.
现在他正在领取风险津贴
Now he's collecting hazard pay with his feet kicked up.
我表弟的背上有一个洞...
My cousin got a hole in his back--
好了 该说的我都说了
All right, I'm done talking!
马上把面具摘下来
Take your masks off right now!
我们为啥要这样做
Why the fuck would we do that?
因为是我要你们这么做的 这就是为什么...
Because I told you to, that's why--
-去你的 沃尔夫 -操你大爷的
- Fuck you, Wolf. - Fuck you.
大家最好都冷静下来
Everybody better calm down!
你为啥要打开枪套
Yo, why you open your holster?
我不会再问你们第二遍
I'm not gonna ask you again.
你为啥要打开枪套
Why did you open your fucking holster?
道基 该死的 我了解你 我认识你的家人
Dougie, goddamn it, I know you. I know your family.
-我不想伤害... -你也想杀了我们吗 猪头
- I don't wanna hurt-- - You wanna kill us too, pig?
-去你妈的... -他妈的往后退
- Fuck you-- - Back the fuck up and put--
嘿 嘿
Hey, hey!
你他妈的是谁啊
Who the fuck are you?
你在为你表弟的事儿生气
You're angry about your cousin.
而我也在生气
I'd be angry, too.
不管是谁干的 都应该被绳之以法
And whoever did it should be brought to justice.
如果是该死的警长开的枪
How is that gonna happen if it was the fuckin'
那会怎么样
sheriff who pulled the trigger?
尤其是如果是该死的警长... 对吧
Especially if it was the fuckin' sheriff... right?
如果这都能奏效 那我们就必须遵守同样的规则
We all gotta play by the same rules if this is gonna work.
治安官现在在哪儿
Where is the sheriff, right now?
可能是在佛罗里达州或其他地方 晒着他的糊状屁股
Probably Florida or something, tanning his pasty ass.
好吧 但他不在这里
Right. But he's not here.
这里没有人与你表弟的枪击案有关
No one here was involved with your cousin's shooting.
对吗
Correct?
好的
Okay.
现在 我们会给你们让路
Now, we'll get out of your way.
没有人会受到伤害
There's no harm done.
我为你的家人逝去表示遗憾
And I'm sorry for your family.
这是一个很大的成功
Well, that was a big success.
真高兴你今天来了
Really glad you came along today.
我告诉过你 在这里
I told you that around here,
联系当局只会让事情变得更糟
contacting authorities only makes things worse.
那么你的意义何在
Then what is the point of you?
你到底是做什么的
What exactly do you do?
是啊 不如你来告诉我该怎么做 那就太好了
Yeah, why don't you tell me how to do my job? That'd be great.
我在自己家里没有安全感
I don't feel safe in my own house.
我应该可以打电话给警察
I should be able to call the police and have
然后有信心我的担忧会得到解决
the confidence that my concerns will be addressed.
女士 这整个州的法律
Ma'am, there isn't enough law
都不足以让你感到安全
in this whole state to make you feel safe.
现在 如果你想住在峡谷的中央
Now, you want to live out in the middle of a canyon,
那你就只能靠你自己了
you're on your own.
如果你处理不好这个问题 我听说他们
And if you can't handle that, I hear they're putting
在大学附近建了一些漂亮的公寓
up some nice condos over by the college.
或者你可以回去“好轻松”
Or you could go back to The Big Easy.
你好
Hello?
亚瑟 我是桑德拉
Arthur. It's Sandra.
桑德拉 现在是凌晨零时
Sandra, it's- 00 in the morning.
你的院子里有两个人
You've got two guys in your yard
想闯进我的地盘
trying to get on my property.
噢 什么
Oh. What?
什么... 什么人 你在说什么
What-- What guys, what are you talking about?
猎人
The hunters.
我不会让他们进入峡谷的
I wouldn't let them into the canyon,
所以他们爬上了你的栅栏
so they climbed your fence.
那你想让我怎么做
So, what do you want me to do about it?
有持枪的人
There's guys with guns
未经允许就从你家的后门经过
walking by your back door without permission.
这和打猎无关
It's not about the hunting.
这些家伙不断回来
These guys keep coming back.
你认为这是为了什么
Why do you think that is?
我不知道 桑德拉
I don't-- I don't know, Sandra.
你为什么这么在乎
Why do you care so much?
继续睡吧
Go back to sleep.
闻起来像只鹿 拉出来的屎也像只鹿
Smells like a deer, shit's like a deer,
-是只该死的鹿 -闭嘴
- it's a fucking deer. - Shut up.
在那里待上几个小时
up there for a couple hours,
她就会从我们身边儿经过
she'll walk right past us.
你他妈的在这里干什么
The fuck are you doing here?
你在跟踪我吗
Are you following me around?
你想说点什么
You trying to make some kind of point?
那是你妈妈吗
Is that your mother?
是的 是啊 那又怎样
Yes. Yeah, what of it?
我母亲是一名风琴手
My mother was an organist.
在新奥尔良的教堂里
In our church back in New Orleans.
她过去经常玩这个
She used to play this.
她是吗
She did?
“美丽的救世主”
"Beautiful Savior."
请坐
Please, be seated.
上帝存善
God is good.
总是如此
All the time.
上帝存善
God is good.
兄弟姐妹们
Brothers and sisters,
让我们打开马太福音 第六章 第25节
let us open to Matthew, Chapter six, verse 25.
“因此 我告诉你们不要为你们的生活担忧
"Therefore, I tell you, do not worry about your life,
你们要吃什么 喝什么 或是关于你们的身体
what you will eat or drink or about your body.
你们要穿什么
What you will wear.
难道生命不比食物更重要
Is not life more than food
身体不比衣服更重要吗”
and the body more than clothes?"
你相信这些玩意儿
You believe in this stuff?
我做过一次 是的
I did, once. Yeah.
来这里找她 让她开心
Come here for her. Make her happy.
是的 我知道所有的情况
Yeah. I know all about that.
她在生活中忍受了很多糟心事儿
She put up with a lot of shit in her life.
她已经习惯了不快乐的生活
She got used to being unhappy.
是啊
Yeah.
是的
我的母亲也是如此
My mother had that.
她从未原谅我把她带到这里来
She never forgave me for bringing her up here.
她讨厌寒冷
She hated the cold.
每个人都讨厌寒冷
Everyone hates the cold.
真希望她能听到你这么说
I wish she could hear you say that.
我的母亲从未满足于此
My mother was never content.
她会抓住20年前发生的事情不放
She'd hold onto stuff that happened 20 years ago,
就像是昨天发生的一样
like it happened yesterday.
一切都是一场战斗
Everything was a battle.
有时我很想知道
I wonder sometimes.
你为什么选择成为现在的自己
Why do you choose to be the person you are?
就像 你只是不管在你之前发生过什么
Like, you're just Whatever happened before you.
也许打破这种循环需要某种牺牲
Maybe it takes some kind of sacrifice to break the cycle.
-阿门 -阿门
- Amen. - Amen.
让我们站起来...
Let us rise and--
我不知道你为什么来这里 但你现在得离开
I don't know why you came here but you need to leave now.
你为什么要这么做
Why are you doing this?
这对你没有帮助 并不能让你得到什么
This doesn't help you. Doesn't get you anything.
你到底想要什么
What do you want?
你听到我说的了吗
Are you hearing me?
你为什么不进来
Why don't you come inside?
什么
What?
进来吧
Just come inside.
我们可以解决的
We can work it out.
我知道你想要什么
I know what you want.
来吧
Come on.
怎么了 来吧
What's the matter? Come on.
嗯 怎么了
Huh? What's the matter?
来吧 你要去哪里
Come on. Eh, where ya going!
惊喜
Surprise.
我很抱歉 我很抱歉
I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
你看起来想来点这个
You look like you could use one of these.
-很高兴见到你 -我喜欢你的裙子
- Good to see you. - I love your dress.
桑德拉 说实话 是不是穿得有点过了
Sandra, tell me, honestly, is it-- is it too much?
不 该死 你看起来很棒
No. Hell no. You look amazing.
干杯
Cheers.
你喜欢这个聚会吗
Are you enjoying the party?
说实话 他能让我加入真是太好了
Honestly, it's so nice of him to let me join for a bit.
他的房子很漂亮 对吧
His house is so nice, right?
他告诉我是他自己设计的
He told me he designed it himself.
是的 我敢打赌是他自己设计的
Yeah, I'll bet he did.
噢...
Oh...
什么 什么 什么
What? What? What?
那边儿那个人正在认真打量你呢
That guy over there was checking you out pretty hard.
噢 天哪 不
Oh, my God. No.
我认识他
It-- I know him.
这没关系 没什么
It doesn't matter. It's nothing.
噢 好吧
Oh, okay.
我有堆积如山的试卷要批改
Well, I have a mountain of exam papers to grade
-所以祝你有一个美好的夜晚 -不 不是这样的
- so you have a good night. - No, it's not like that.
圣诞快乐
Merry Christmas.
穿着打扮相当得体
Clean up nice.
所以 你... 你在这里做什么
So, what are you-- What are you doing here?
噢 我和苏珊是老交情了
Oh. Me and Susan go back a ways.
上高中的时候
High school.
你可以想象一下
You can imagine.
听着 我很高兴能遇到你
Look, I'm glad I ran into you.
嗯 前几天我气炸了
Um, I blew my top the other day.
我该向你道歉
I owe you an apology.
我不应该那样对你说话
I shouldn't talk to you like that.
好吧 我们没有被电锯锯死
Well, we didn't get chainsaw-ed.
这是个好日子
That's a good day.
是的
Yeah.
你在新奥尔良时做过什么工作
What kind of work did you do back in New Orleans?
你有留意过我
You looked me up.
嗯 好吧 我有一种预感
Huh. Well, I had a hunch.
你在农场的表现
The way you handled yourself back at that farm,
还有烟头和密封袋
and cigarette butts and Ziploc.
干得漂亮 侦探
Excellent work, detective.
噢 不
Oh, no.
我只是个出身低微的副警长
I'm just a humble sheriff's deputy.
当一个大城市的警察是什么感觉
What was it like being a big city cop?
和在这里当警察一样
Same as being a cop here,
除了备份和基础技术
except with backup and basic technology.
很有趣
Very funny.
不 就是你想的那样
No, it is what you think it is.
大城市有大城市的问题
Big cities have big city problems.
我做不到
I couldn't do it.
在这里也不是走马观花
It's not a walk in the park here, either
但至少你能知道羊和狼的区别
but at least you know the sheep from the wolves.
这就是你成为警察的原因
Is that why you became a cop?
这个嘛...
Well...
我猜是我高中时的橄榄球教练对我的影响
I guess it was my high school football coach, actually.
他当过警察
Uh, he'd been a cop
我对他很仰慕
and looked up to him.
所以我想我只是在做他做过的事情
So I guess I just figured I'd do what he did.
那么你呢
Well? What about you?
我想为我的社区服务
I wanted to serve my community.
噢
Oh.
很好的理由
Pretty good reason.
我还记得我们第一次来这里的时候
I remember when we first came here.
我觉得我们仿佛回到了过去
And I felt like we'd gone back in time.
你看看那些山
You look at those mountains
你可以看到所有的方式都回到起点
and you can see all the way back to the beginning,
在根本没有人的时候
before there were any people at all.
只不过是只熊
Just bears.
我记得我站在那片田野里
I remember standing in that field.
哭了
Crying.
因为它是如此... 未遭破坏
Because it was so... unspoiled.
我从未有过这种感觉
I'd never felt anything like that.
我知道当雪融化时
And I know when the snow melts,
我会再次有那种感觉
I'll get to feel that way again.
不 是的 是的
No, yeah, it's, uh,
它很雄伟
it's pretty majestic.
你很会说话
You got quite a way with words.
我教的是公开演讲
I teach public speaking.
啊
Ah.
那么 到底是什么让你来到这里
So what brought you up here anyway?
终身职位
Tenure track.
不 我是说
No, I mean.
我不知道有多少
I don't know a lot of beat cops
巡警在大学里上课
that teach college classes.
你是在问我为什么退出警队
You're asking why I quit the force?
我很好奇
I'm curious.
问和想知道不是一回事儿
Well, asking and wanting to know are not the same thing.
给我讲讲
Try me.
我在新奥尔良出生长大
I was born and raised in New Orleans.
新奥尔良是我的家
New Orleans was my home.
现在我住在这里
Now I live out here.
我一生都想成为一名警察
All my life, I wanted to be a police officer.
而现在我再也不可能再戴上
And now there is no way I would ever
那个该死的警徽了
put on that motherfucking badge again.
你觉得原因是什么
Why do you think that is?
你必须拔出你的武器
You had to draw your weapon.
你必须向某人开枪
You had to shoot somebody.
这是你能想到的最糟糕的事情吗
That's the worst thing you can think of?
他们让我们被淹死 他们让我的人民被淹死
They let us drown. They let my people drown.
而他们却不屑一顾
And they didn't give a goddamn about it.
你知道吗
And you know what?
这本不值得惊讶
It should have been no surprise.
而这就是事情的真相
That's just the way it goes.
我母亲认为上帝会拯救我们
My mother thought God would save us.
以前曾想把她弄出来
Tried to get her out before.
但她听不进去
She wouldn't hear it.
她认为上帝会把我们从飓风中拯救出来
She thought that God would save us from the hurricane.
我无法改变她的想法
And I couldn't change her mind.
所以我离开了她 因为我还有工作要做
So I left her because I had a job to do.
然后我不得不去把她从那该死的超级穹顶里挖出来
And then I had to go dig her out of the fucking Superdome.
然而她再也没有回来
And she never came back from that.
这不是你回来的原因
That's not something you come back from.
我们失败了
We failed.
我保护不了她
I couldn't protect her.
这也就是我辞职的原因
That's why I quit.
很抱歉 我不知道这些
I'm sorry, I didn't know.
噢 嘿 格雷琴 你还好吗 请进 请进
Oh hey, Gretchen. You okay? Come in, come in.
所以 呃...
So, um...
-我想问你一些事情 -没问题
- I wanted to ask you something. - Mm-hm.
还记得之前你提到过的助教的事情吗
You know how you mentioned the T.A. thing?
好吧 嗯... 我想和你谈谈这件事情
Well, um... I'd like to take you up on that.
我是说 如果还可以的话
I mean, if it's still available.
是的 当然了
Yeah, of course.
只要亚瑟不介意就行
As long as it's alright with Arthur.
噢 我相信他还有很多人
Oh, I'm sure he has plenty of other people.
有什么不一样吗
Did something change?
如果我告诉你 你要保证不说出去
If I tell you, you have to promise you won't say anything.
告诉我什么
Tell me what?
昨晚派对结束后 他...
Last night after the party, he--
...呃...
...uh...
他走进书房
He came into the study.
我当时正在批改试卷
I was grading papers.
他说他在搬运木柴时拉伤了肌肉
He said he'd pulled a muscle carrying firewood.
他浑身酸痛 睡不着觉
He was sore and he couldn't sleep.
他有一些乳液 他想让我帮他涂上
He had some lotion and he wanted me to put it on for him,
所以... 所以我就照做了
so-- so I did.
他碰你了吗
Did he touch you?
我帮他在肩膀上涂抹了乳液
I put the lotion on the shoulders for him
就是这样
and that was it.
格雷琴 你大可不必这么做
Gretchen, you do not have to accept this.
我是说 我已经答应了
I mean, I agreed to do it.
这没什么大不了的
It wasn't a big deal.
我们不必再谈论这个问题了 我只是 呃...
We don't have to talk about this anymore, I just, uh...
我现在只想帮你做助教
I'd just rather T.A. for you now.
好吧
Yeah.
呃 赞成的请举手
Uh, all those in favor?
好的 有反对的吗
Okay. Opposed?
吉德里教授 再一次
Professor Guidry, again.
好了 各位
Well, folks.
看起来我们已经有了前三名
Looks like we have our top three.
祝贺大家 做得很好
Congratulations. Well done.
我并不是有意要刁难你
I don't mean to be difficult
但我们都同意 为了我们部门的未来
but we all agreed it was important for the future
努力提高包容性是很重要的
of our department to try to be more inclusive.
呃 我想我们确实已经尽力了
Uh, I think we did try.
现在我们有了名单
And now that we have our list,
重要的是我们都要团结起来支持这一方案
it's important that we all rally behind it.
我见过院长在感觉到不和谐的情况下
I've seen the Dean use the budget to stall appointments
利用预算来拖延任命
if he senses discord.
而我们这里有三位优秀的候选人
And we have three fine candidates here
他们可以真正地与我们的部门一起成长
who could really grow with our department.
所以 让我们...
So, let's...
我们不要错过这个机会
let's not blow this opportunity.
基于以上 祝各位圣诞快乐
And on that note, Merry Christmas, everyone.
上帝保佑
God bless.
还有 呃 嘿 明年见
And, um, hey, see you all next year.
是的 好吧 一旦我们...
Yeah. Well, once we--
一旦... 我想这取决于...
Once-- I think it's up to the...
失陪一下
Excuse me for one second.
我记得我们说过 我们会尽力向院长
I thought we said that we would try to recommend
推荐至少一位有色人种
at least one person of color to the dean.
恰恰相反 我们明确表示
On the contrary, we explicitly said
这不是为了填补配额
that this was not about filling a quota.
我不是这个意思
That's not what I'm saying.
你刚才真的这么说了...
You literally just said that--
不 不 你没听懂我的意思
No, no, you're not listening to me.
不 我很确定你明白这个概念...
No, I'm pretty sure you understand the concept of--
我是说 我们应该试着推荐
I said that we should try to recommend.
不是雇佣 是推荐
Not hire, recommend.
就是这样
That's all.
三个人的名单上只有一个人的名字 我们就不能这样做吗
One name on a list of three, and we can't do that?
所以 一个配额
So, a quota.
我们是有选择的 亚瑟
We had options, Arthur.
我们都认为这很重要
And we agreed it was important.
-你是这么说的 对吧 -对
- You said that. Right? - Yes.
我不知道你在说什么 桑德拉
I don't know where you're going with this, Sandra.
我是想提醒你...
I'm trying to remind you--
我百分百地相信我们考虑到了每一个人
I'm 100% confident that we considered everyone--
我只是想表达我们之间所达成的共识...
I'm trying to express what we agreed--
桑德拉 这与你无关
Sandra, this is not about you.
我知道这与我无关
Oh, I know this is not about me.
这是关于雇佣最适合这份工作的人 任期
This is about hiring the best person for the job. Period.
但如果名单上的人都是白人
But if everyone on the list is white,
-那我们该怎么... -桑德拉 已经结束了
- then how are we supposed to-- - Sandra. It's over.
这个过程是公平的
The process was fair!
现在已经结束了 而我们正在向前迈进
Now it's over and we are moving on.
我不会允许院长因为我们被身份政治分心
I will not allow the dean to cut this department to ribbons
而把这个部门搞得一团糟
because we got distracted by identity politics.
-身份政治 -是的 在我的眼皮底下不行
- Identity politics? - Yeah. Not on my watch.
坦率地讲 我非常反感你在这里面读出了
And quite frankly, I take great offense that you're reading
-某种偏见 -事情就是这样的
- some kind of bias into this. - This is how it happens.
就在这里 它是如何崩溃的...
Right here is how it all breaks down--
你知道吗 饶了我吧...
You know what, spare me--
这是一个关于这个过程的大合唱...
It's this whole big song and dance about the process--
而现在你很生气 因为你没有得到你想要的
And now you're mad that you didn't get what you wanted.
我们说我们在乎对与错...
We say we care about right and wrong--
-你怎么敢 -但最终 这其实
- How dare you? - But in the end, it's really
只是为了赢 不是吗
just about winning, isn't it?
你来了 我们雇用了你 不是吗
You're here. We hired you, didn't we?
啊
Huh?
你的背怎么样了 亚瑟 我听说你肌肉拉伤了
How's your back, Arthur? I hear you pulled a muscle.
我觉得你需要花点
Think you need to take
时间独处 也许下个学期可以休息一下
some time to yourself, maybe take the next term off!
去看看心理医生吧
Go see a shrink!
她过得很艰难 你知道吗
She's having a hard time, you know?
她只是... 她最近母亲刚过世 所以...
She just-- she lost her mom recently, so...
格雷琴
Gretchen.
来吧 我们要去见院长
Come on. We're going to the Dean.
我们现在就得走
We have to go right now.
什么 你在说什么...
What? What are you talking...
我们不能让他们逍遥法外 再也不会了
We cannot let them get away with this. Not anymore.
我们每一次都要进行反击
We have to fight back every time.
要一直这样 否则就会永无宁日
All the time or this is going to go on forever.
你说了什么吗
Did you say something?
你说了什么
What did you say?
我没有说你的名字
I didn't say your name.
我以为你明白我是多么努力工作才走到今天的
I thought you understood how hard I worked to get here.
格雷琴 我... 相信我 我相信
Gretchen. I-- Believe me, I do.
但你有权利生气
But you have a right to be angry.
你不应该因为
And you shouldn't punish yourself
一些不是你的错而惩罚自己
for something that's not your fault.
你以为我就是这么做的吗
Is that what you think I'm doing?
女士们 一切都还好吗
Ladies, everything all right?
我很抱歉
I'm so... Sorry.
我需要为我的行为道歉
I need to apologize for my behavior.
我说的话太过分了
What I said was completely out of line.
而你是对的
And you're right.
我或许应该休息一段时间
I should probably take some time off.
嘿 伙计们 你们的表现如何
Hey, fellas! How'd you do?
看看这个人 你他妈的告诉我
Look at this man, you fuckin' tell me!
天哪
Jesus fucking Christ.
你知道你在干什么吗
What do you think you're doing?
桑德拉
Sandra?
真是不可思议 这是我的财产
Unbelievable. This is my property.
桑德拉 拜托
Sandra, come on.
桑德拉
Sandra.
天哪
Jesus.
嘿 桑德拉
Hey! Sandra!
是啊 你现在觉得自己长大了吗
Yeah, you feel big now?
你屠杀了小鹿宝宝 你真是个大男人
You massacre at tiny baby deer and you're such a big man.
管好你自己的事儿就好了
Just mind your own goddamn business.
是啊 我也想当妈妈
Yeah, I'd kinda like to do the mama, too.
你知道吗 桑德拉 我真的需要你
'Kay, you know what, Sandra? I really need you
-马上离开 -闭上你的臭嘴
- to walk away right now-- - Oh, shut the fuck up!
是啊 闭上你的臭嘴 嗯
Yeah, shut the fuck up, huh?
我累了 我对你感到厌烦至极
I'm tired. I'm so tired of you.
你知道吗 前几天她也来过我家
You know, she came to my house the other day, too.
我跟你说过吗
Did I tell you that?
随时都可以回来 宝贝
Come back anytime, baby.
你再回来 我就他妈的杀了你
You come back here again, I'll fucking kill you.
我向上帝发誓 我他妈的会杀了你
I swear to God, I'll fucking kill you.
天哪 你没事儿吧 伙计
Holy shit, are you okay, man?
啊 他妈的
Ah. Fuck.
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
你他妈的是在跟我开玩笑吗
Are you fucking kidding me?
是的
Yeah.
我们在这儿
We're here.
We're here!
我们在这儿
嘿 我要抽根烟
Hey, I'm gonna have a smoke.
不 你要干嘛 你要干嘛
No, what are you doing? What are you doing?
噢... 不 不 不 不
Oh-- No, no, no, no!